Guide to the Paul C. Edwards Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Outgoing Correspondence, Series 2
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1960 May 13 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Edwards, Carroll, 1960 August 20 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Edwards, Edgar, 1960 August 28 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sterling, J. E. Wallace, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- General Files, Series 3
  - Stanford University Alumni Association, idea and suggestions on improving its effectiveness, 1942 October 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Associates, Address: Eight Years of Service, 1942 September 30 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Associates, Articles of Incorporation, 1940 October 17 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Associates, proposal for Stanford Council, 1948 May 20 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Associates, dinner, 1942 October 13 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Associates, endowments, 1943, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Associates, committee on exceptional students, 1940 February - 1942 October (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Associates, Government Board, meetings of, 1942 October 13 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Associates, kitchen cabinet meeting, 1942 August 22 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Associates, committee on public relations, 1941 July - 1942 July (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Associates, University publications memo, 1943 October (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Research Institute (SRI), associate pledges, 1949 January 21 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - SRI, Director's Report, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - SRI, financial statements, 1949 September (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - SRI, financial statements, 1949 October (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - SRI, financial statements, 1949 December (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - SRI, financial statements from J. E. Hobson, 1951 January - march (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - SRI, financial statements, 1951 February 28 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - SRI, financial statements, 1951 March 31 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - SRI, financial statements dated 4/20/21, 8/28/51, and 5/20/52, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - SRI, Italian project, 1951 May 24 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - SRI, Objectives and Policies, 1950 March 31 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - SRI, minutes of meetings of Executive Committee of the Board of Directors, 1949 February - 1952 February (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - SRI, summary of US Government projects, 1951 August 14 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Stanford University Board of Trustees, composition of the board, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Stanford University Board of Trustees, Crother's Hall dedication, 1948 October 23 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Stanford University Board of Trustees, Committee on Finance: agenda, 11/17/49, memo, 4/18/45 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "Rising Costs of Education" published by San Francisco Chronicle, 1951 August 19 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Financial report, examination of financial statements, 1948 August 31 - 1949 August 31 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Stanford University Board of Trustees, gift procurement, committee on, 1944 March 16 - 1951 August 31 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Stanford University Board of Trustees, Investements, College, 1951 June 23 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Stanford University Board of Trustees, Investments, Committee on, 1950 January 20 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Stanford University Board of Trustees, Investments, 1951 June 4 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Stanford University Board of Trustees, land use survey report, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Stanford University Board of Trustees, Menlo lot bids, 1950 December (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Stanford University Board of Trustees, planning and development committee, 1945 July 19 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Stanford University Board of Trustees, school humanities, social sciences, physical sciences, and biological sciences, reorganization of, 1948 September 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Stanford University Board of Trustees, Tresidder memorial, fund committee for, 1948 March (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Stanford University Board of Trustees, trustee organization, study committee on, 1953 October 28 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Stanford University, Board of Trustees, report on unemployment insurance, 1950 August (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Stanford University Board of Trustees, development of additional water resources, 1940 - 1951 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Stanford University Board of Trustees, Women's Club, 1951 September 20 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous: Paul C. Edwards misc. addresses, speeches, etc., 1942 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaenous: Stanford Athletic Board (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous: Stanford Business School, Alumni Association, 1951 November 20 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous: Stanford Fund Committee for Annual Appeal, 1942 October 8 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous: Stanford Futures, 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous: liquor law, repeal of, ASSU, 1951 November 28 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous: Stanford University Medical School, 1945-1951 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous: Stanford University Overseas Studies Program, 1960 November (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous: war council, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1995-048
  - Miscellaneous personal (includes his letter to his brother Emery, 1896; school essays, 1901-03; high school magazine; misc. clippings) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Original Speeches and Papers on the Press (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Original Speeches, Papers, etc. Foreign Policy (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Original Speeches, Essays, Editorials, Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "The San Francisco News" [Sept. 29, 1936] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Poetry by Paul C. Edwards (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Plays by Paul C. Edwards (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Paul C. Edwards Professorship (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Wilbur Memoirs (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Wallace Sterling (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Board of Trustees (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Miscellaneous (club certificates) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Stanford, 1895-1986 (clippings, correspondence, speeches, student memorabilia; includes carbon copies of his letters to administrators about "pee-rade" incident at Stanford 1908; and an 1895 letter by Edwards describing a visit to campus) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Stanford Miscellaneous Papers (memoranda, clippings, correspondence), 1943-86 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, etc. with Harold Fisher and Ernest Hilgard [1952-54] (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Uncommon Man Award (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Retirement Messages (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Obits and Letters of Sympathy (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - A. O. Anderson, correspondence [1910-1919] (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - A. O. Anderson, correspondence [Jan.- March 1920] (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - A. O. Anderson, correspondence [April - Dec. 1920] (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - A. O. Anderson, correspondence [1921] (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - A. O. Anderson, correspondence[1922-37] (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Burkhardt, San Francisco News, correspondence [1923] (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Burkhardt, San Francisco News, correspondence [1924] (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Burkhardt, San Francisco News, correspondence [1925] (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Burkhardt, San Francisco News, correspondence [1926] (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Burkhardt, San Francisco News, correspondence [1927-32] (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - William B. Colver, General Editorial Manager, Scripps-Howard, correspondence [1920-22] (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - William B. Colver, General Editorial Manager, Scripps-Howard, correspondence [Jan. - June 1923] (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - William B. Colver, General Editorial Manager, Scripps-Howard, correspondence [July - Dec. 1923] (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - William B. Colver, General Editorial Manager, Scripps-Howard, correspondence [1924-25] (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - William G. Chandler, General Business Manager, Scripps-Howard, correspondence [1929] (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - J. C. Harper, correspondence [1916-1930] (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Howard, Roy, correspondence [1921-56] (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Leech, E.T., Editor Memphis Press, correspondence [1919-1922] (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Mayborn, W.C., Fort Worth Press, correspondence [1921-28] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Mellett, Lowell, correspondence [1926-1931] (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mosher, C. F., correspondence [1922] (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Neave, H. E., Treasurer, Scripps-Howard, correspondence [1924-32] (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Paine, Robert F., correspondence [1909-1929] (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Parker, G. B., General Editorial Executive, Scripps-Howard, correspondence [1925-1932] (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Pinkerton, Roy; Editor, San Diego Sun, correspondence [1924-25] (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Porterfield, W.H., correspondence [1924-26] (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Sanders, G. V., Houston Press, correspondence [1921] (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Siler, L.M.; Fort Worth, correspondence [1921-23] (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Sharp, Tom; Memphis Press, correspondence [1922] (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Scripps, E.W., correspondence [1911-1917] (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Scripps, Robert P., correspondence [1919-20] (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Scripps, Robert P., correspondence [1921-22] (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Scripps, Robert P., correspondence [1923-32] (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Stern, Max, correspondence [1924-32] (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Talley, Robert, correspondence [1923] (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Torbert, Harold, correspondence [1928-32] (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Woon, Basil, correspondence [1917-19] (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Scripps-Howard, Miscellaneous (correspondence, 1924-44, minutes of editorial conference, 1923-24, investment reports, 1958-59) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - "The Dallas Dispatch,” correspondence and clippings[1909-1917] (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - "The Dallas Dispatch,” issues [1916] (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Excerpted Material for History of "Houston Press" [1911-61] (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "Houston Press,” correspondence and reports [1906-11] (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Early Editions "Houston Press" (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - First Edition of "The Houston Press" (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Houston, correspondence (some personal, some related to Houston Press) [1912] (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Houston Press" [1913], correspondence (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "The Houston Press" [1914], correspondence (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "The Houston Press" [1915], correspondence (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "The Houston Press" [1916], correspondence (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "The Houston Press" [1917-18], correspondence (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "The Houston Press" [1916], issues (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "The Houston Press" [1951], issues (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "The Houston Press" [1955-57], issues (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - History of "The Houston Press", by H.C. Waters (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Story of "The Houston Press", by H.C. Waters (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "The Houston Press" 50th. Anniversary (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "Fort Worth Press" [1919-21], correspondence and reports (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "San Diego Sun" [1927-31], correspondence (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "San Diego Sun" [1930], issues (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Letters, Move from San Diego to San Francisco (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - "San Diego Sun" - Talks with Readers [1927-32], clippings (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Special excerpted columns: "San Diego Sun" - Talks with Readers [1927-31] (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - "San Diego Sun" - Talks with Readers [1928] (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - "San Diego Sun" - Talks with Readers [1929] (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "San Diego Sun" - Talks with Readers [1930] (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - "San Diego Sun" - Talks with Readers [1931] (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - "San Diego Sun" - Talks with Readers [1932] (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "San Francisco News", issues (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Conference, Institute of Pacific Relations [Aug. 1936] (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "San Francisco News", Editorials and Articles, 1933-1951 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Misc. Newspaper Material (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Typescript memoirs:
    - Growing up (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Stanford, early (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - San Francisco 1906-08 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Dallas 1908-11 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Houston 1911-16 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Dallas 1916-22 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - San Francisco 1922-25 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - San Diego 1925-33 [1] (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - San Diego 1925-33 [2] (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - San Diego 1925-33 [3] (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - San Diego 1925-33 [4] (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - San Francisco [1933-55] (1) (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - San Francisco [1933-55] (2) (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - San Francisco / Los Altos [1955-62] (Box 4, Folder 14)